# WILLIAM GRUNDLER

Simi Valley, CA 93065

Phone: 805-746-9371 | Email: wrgrundler@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamgrundler

GitHub: https://github.com/wrg93 | Portfolio: https://williamgrundlerportfolio.herokuapp.com/

#### SUMMARY

Full stack web developer utilizing background in opera and research analysis to creatively develop and integrate back-end. Known for an ability to create and integrate databases in various libraries. With a proven aptitude for learning languages and data analysis, excited to work with a creative and driven team.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: MongoDB, Mongoose, JavaScript, MERN, MySQL, Sequelize, React, jQuery,

Express, Node, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Applications: Excel, Word, Powerpoint, Logic Pro, Finale

#### **P**ROJECTS

FidoFriend | GitHub: https://github.com/wrg93/project-3 | Website: https://young-refuge-69490.herokuapp.com

Responsive social media web application for dog owners built with the MERN stack (mongoDB, Express, React, Node.js). Responsible for creating the database and implementing Redux for state management. Also created sign in and log in using Passport and JSON Web Token.

StoryTime | GitHub: https://github.com/wrg93/StoryTime | Website: https://fathomless-waters-70908.herokuapp.com

Responsive web application which customizes children's stories. Built with Sequel, Sequelize, Express, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap. Responsible for creating API routes to the database. Responsible for implementing Nodemailer.

Get Prepared | GitHub: https://github.com/wrg93/project1 |

Website: https://wrg93.github.io/project1

Responsive web application which helps the user prepare for natural disasters in their area. Responsible for generating lists based on user input and for using local storage to add hyperlinked items to the basket. Created using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML and CSS.

#### EXPERIENCE

05/2018-Present The Greenspan Company - Encino, CA

Research Analyst

- Has mastered numerous data-gathering applications
- Has optimized generation of reports leading to increase in sales
- Has thrived under high pressure
- Has trained new hires

## 10/2019-Present Canoga Park Lutheran Church - Canoga Park, CA

Music Director and Choral Administrator

- Has researched and selected choral pieces for weekly rehearsals and performances
- Has provided administrative support for the choral department

## 01/2017-10/2019 Grace Lutheran Church - Ventura, CA

Music Director and Choral Administrator

- Researched and selected choral pieces for weekly rehearsals and performances
- Provided administrative support for the choral department

# 02/2018-05/2018 **24 Hour Fitness - Oxnard, CA**

Night Service Representative

- Provided customer service
- Managed gym premises

## 09/2015-Present Santa Clarita Master Chorale- Santa Clarita, CA

Soloist and Ringer

# 11/2015-08/2017 Young Musicians Foundation - Los Angeles, CA

Vocal Teaching Artist: Choir Instructor at Will Rogers Middle School, Hope Street Family Center, Carthay Environmental Studies Magnet School, and New Los Angeles Charter Middle School

- Organized musical programs and performances
- Conducted multiple choirs
- Researched and selected choral pieces

### 06/2015-01/2017 First United Methodist Church of Santa Monica - Santa Monica, CA

Tenor Section Leader

# 12/2013-04/2015 Northridge United Methodist Church - Northridge, CA

Tenor Section Leader

## 02/2012-Present JA Vocal Music/Sound Check Music - Northridge, CA

Private Instructor in Voice, Acting, Piano, Composition, and Theory

### **EDUCATION**

Bootcamp Certificate: University of California, Los Angeles, CA

Bachelor of Music in Classical Vocal Performance: California State University, Northridge, CA